安德鲁
Andrew
旧   金   山
2014年
安德鲁
Andrew
不
No
安德鲁
Andrew
不
No
昨晚数千人聚集在一起
Thousands gathered
汇集到湾区
in the Bay Area last night
纪念2014年遇袭的受害者
to honor the victims of the 2014 attacks.
参与抗议的一部分人
Part of a wave of memorials and protests
要求搜捕巨兽的帝王组织
demanding that the secretive monster-hunting coalition
为伤亡负责
known as Monarch be held accountable.
近日全球海洋生物死亡数量飙升
The recent spike in mass die-offs in the world's oceans
可能以试图锁定与追踪已经失踪五年的哥斯拉有关
could be caused by efforts to locate and track Godzilla,who hasn't been seen in over five years.
帝王组织高层将再次面临危机
Top brass at the mysterious Monarch organization.will face another intense grilling
因为政府已在持续推动猎杀泰坦巨兽的行动
as the government continues.to push for extermination of the Titans.
外界盛传 帝王组织可能窝藏了自2014年袭击以来所发现的众多新怪兽
And rumors persist that Monarch may be hiding.even more creatures discovered since the attacks of 2014.
这次历史性悲剧彻底的改变世界
A historic tragedy that changed the world
让全球得知怪兽是真实存在的
as we know it forever.The day the world discovered that monsters are real.
该死
Shit
该死 该死 该死
Shit, shit, shit
-哦 -麦蒂?
- Oh... - Maddie?
早上好
Good morning
-早上好  妈   - 我的天
- Good morning, Mom  - Oh, God
-呃 -好吧
- Uh... - Okay.
我做了早餐
I made us breakfast.
哦 是
It's, uh...
鸡蛋 吐司 和烤焦的培根
Eggs, toast, and what was once bacon.
你推荐我吃哪个?
And which do you recommend?
吐司和鸡蛋吧
The toast and eggs.
谢谢
Thank you.
要来点咖啡吗
Coffee?
你刚在忙什么?
What were you working on?
哦 我只是在看菜谱
Um, I was looking at recipes.
吐司的?
For toast?
老爸给我发邮件了
Dad's been emailing me.
但他看起来不错
But he looks good.
很健康
Healthy.
你有回复吗?
Have you responded?
还没有
Not yet.
麦蒂森 我只是不想你受伤
Madison, I just don't want to see you get hurt.
我知道
I know.
尤其是现在发生的一切
Especially with everything that's going on right now.
妈 我知道
Mom, I know.
你看 我知道这一路走来对你来说不容易
Listen, I know things haven't been easy for you.
但我们必须要一起共度难关
But we're gonna get through this.Together.
到底发生什么了 ?
You sure he's gonna be okay?
他现在在全世界最安全的地方
He is in the safest place that he could be right now.
你想同听好消息吗?
You wanna hear some good news?
我完成了
I finished it.
真的吗?
Really?
你觉的这会起作用吗?
You think it's gonna work?
它会起作用的
It's gonna work.
不会有事的
It's gonna be okay.
拉塞尔博士
Doctor Russell,
我们需要你来中控室
we need you in Containment.
我马上来
I'm on my way.
帝王组织前哨61号基地
中国云南热带雨林
到底发生什么了 ?
What the hell happened?
不知道
No idea.
她本来睡的很香
She was sleeping like a baby
知道一小时前 然后突然暴走
until an hour ago, and then, boom.
她的辐射值瞬间爆表
Her radiation levels went through the roof.
仿佛被认为启动
Almost like something triggered it.
谢谢 蒂姆
Thanks, Tim.
我来接手吧 不如你去休息会?
I can take it from here. Why don't you get some rest?
不行
No way.
我不想错过这个
Sleep or no sleep, I'm not missing this.
封锁小组进入备战位置
Containment team, move into primary position.
-镇静剂? -没有用
- Sedatives? - No effect.
她迫不及待要出世了
This thing wants to be born.
启动应急程序
Emergency protocol is in effect.
十秒后开启生化封锁
Ten seconds to biocontainment.
她要出生了
Her time has come.
见识一下泰坦龙蝶吧
Meet Titanus mosura.
或者我们可以叫她
Or as we like to call her...
摩斯拉
Mothra.
难以置信
Incredible.
激活封锁网络
Activating containment grid.
-警告  -怎么了?
- Warning. - What's happening?
警告
Warning.
情况不对劲
Something's really wrong here.
封锁系统失效了
Containment systems are failing.
周界警报响起
Perimeter alarms are going off,
系统完全宕机了
the whole network's going insane.
什么意思? 怎么可能?
What do you mean? How is that possible?
艾玛 我怀疑有人在捣乱
Emma, I think someone else is doing this.
封锁小队 解除戒备
Containment team, stand down.
重复 解除戒备 你们吓到她了
I repeat, stand down. You are scaring her.
不
No
拉塞尔博士 对不起 但你知道程序的
Doctor Russell, I'm sorry. But you know the protocols.
我们必须杀了她
We have to terminate
我会处理这件事
I'll handle this.
妈 不行
Mom  No
麦蒂森 待在这 一定会管用的
Madison, stay here. It's gonna work.
消毒中
Stand clear.
没事的
It's okay.
妈
Mom
麦蒂 等等
Maddie, wait
麦蒂
Maddie
快回来
Get back in here
麦蒂 快回去
Maddie  Go back
妈 我们走吧
Mom  Let's go
妈
Mom
不是吧
Son of a bitch.
真成功了
It worked.
妈?
Mom?
参议员们 我们现在看到的
What we are witnessing here, Senators,
是一个被遗忘的古老超级物种的回归
is the return of an ancient and forgotten super species.
帝王组织参议院听证会
哥斯拉 穆托 金刚
Godzilla, the MUTOs, Kong.
华盛顿特区
我们相信这些泰坦巨兽
We believe that these "Titans"
以及其他与他们一样的生物
and others like them
为我们的生态提供了必要的平衡
provide an essential balance to our world.
有的巨兽可能构成威胁
And while some may pose a threat,
但帝王组织有独特能力
Monarch is uniquely prepared to determine
能辨别这些泰坦中哪些会威胁我们
which of these Titans are here to threaten us
以及哪些能保护我们
and which of these Titans are here to protect us.
谢谢你的五年级历史课演讲 克尔曼先生
Thank you for the fifth grade history lesson, Mr. Coleman.
但我们仍未听到一个充分理由
But we still haven't heard one good reason
为什么帝王组织不应该收归军事管辖范围
why Monarch shouldn't fall under military jurisdiction.
又或者为什么我们不应该消灭这些巨兽
Or why these creatures shouldn't be exterminated.
帝王组织的任务
Monarch was tasked
是发现并摧毁这些放射性巨兽
with finding and destroying these radioactive monsters.
但你们如果无法或者不愿透露
But you either can't or won't tell us
到底有多少巨兽及他们为何出现
how many there are or why they're showing up.
所以现在应该由军队去消灭他们
So, maybe it's time for the military to put them down.
猎杀他们不是明智之举
Killing them would be a mistake.
他们因人类而回归
They returned because of us.
正是我们的原子试爆唤醒了哥斯拉
It was our atomic testing that awoke Gojira.
其他巨兽 如穆托
Other creatures like the MUTOs
是被露天开采和地震勘测引出
from strip mining and seismic surveys.
但他们不是怪兽
But these are not monsters.
他们是动物 只想讨回一个曾经属于他们的世界
They are animals rising to reclaim a world that was once theirs.
这听起来像是
It almost sounds like
你想保护他们 芹泽博士
you're protecting them, Doctor Serizawa.
好像你们佩服他们
As if you admire them.
我敬佩所有的生命形态
I admire all forms of life.
参议员们 如果我们希望存活
Senators, if we hope to survive,
我们必须找到与泰坦巨兽共存的方法
we must find ways to coexist with Titans.
与哥斯拉
With Gojira.
产生一种共生关系
A sort of symbiotic relationship,
如果你愿意的话
if you will.
比如狮子和老鼠
Like the lion and the mouse.
又或者蝎子和青蛙
Or the scorpion and the frog.
所以你想把哥斯拉当成我们的宠物？
So you'd want to make Godzilla our pet?
不
No.
是我们成为他的宠物
We will be his.
呃 不 不 实际上
Uh... No. No, actually.
芹泽博士不是那个意思
That's not what Doctor Serizawa meant.
我们必须走了
We have to go.
并不是说成为他的宠物  - 山姆  我们得走了
No one is implying that we would be Godzilla's or anyone's pet.- Sam, we have to go.
芹泽博士 格雷厄姆博士
Doctor Serizawa, Doctor Graham,
听证会还在进行
this hearing is not adjourned.
芹泽博士 我希望你明白
Doctor Serizawa, I hope you understand
中断离席的后果
the consequences of walking out that door.
呃 不如这样把 参议员
Uh, you know what, Senators,
在我和同事商量的时候
while I confer with my colleagues here,
我给大家放一个简短的
I'm gonna set you up with a very brief
并且十分有趣的纪录片
and pretty fun documentary
关于泰坦巨兽繁殖的
on Titan reproduction.
影片在重点部位都打了马赛克
I think this is the one where the genitals are blurred out.
如果没的话 你们可以投诉我的助手
But if not, you can leave a comment with my assistant.
科罗拉多州
视频在这就断了
The feed cuts out there.
幸存者未能给我们提供
The survivors haven't been able to give us
更多的资讯
much more than what the footage allows.
只说了艾玛和麦蒂森被劫走了
Only that Emma and Madison were the only ones taken.
对不起 马克
I'm sorry, Mark.
我应该在她身边的
I should've been there for her.
他们是谁？
Who are they?
我们还不知道
We don't know yet.
我们相信他们的目标是这个
We believe they were after this.
你们不是吧
You didn't.
奥卡音频机
It's the ORCA.
这就是为什么我们认为他们需要艾玛
Uh, that's why we think they need Emma.
她深信若能复制
She believed that if we could somehow replicate
泰坦用来沟通的声纳
the biosonar the Titans use to communicate...
我知道那是什么鬼东西 我帮忙构建了原型
I know what the hell it is. I helped build the prototype.
他是谁？
Who is he?
呃 山姆克尔曼  我是技术负责人
Uh, Sam Coleman. I'm the head of technology.
我加入了帝王组织 呃 就在你离开后不久
I joined Monarch, uh, shortly after you left.
我是你妻子的粉丝
I'm a big fan of your wife...
只是工作方面
...'s work. And you.
听起来很尴尬 抱歉
That just came out so weird, I'm sorry.
艾玛和我摧毁了原型
Emma and I destroyed the prototype.
然后艾玛决定重建
And then Emma decided to rebuild it.
自从旧金山事件后 她回到了波士顿老家
After San Francisco, she went home to Boston,
花了几年时间研发它
spent years developing it.
他认为这可以
She thought it could help...
可以干嘛？让她扮演上帝？
Would help what? Play God?
不 是为了阻止再次袭击
No. Help prevent another attack.
奥卡是一所研究所的科学项目
ORCA was a grad school science project.
目的是让鲸鱼远离海岸线
It was meant to keep whales away from the shoreline.
不是让你们和那些怪兽沟通
Not so you could talk to your little creatures out there.
听我说 他们会认为那是同类
Listen to me, they'll think it's one of them.
如果你们用了错误音频
You use the wrong frequency on one of 'em
你们将为成千上万次旧金山这样的时间负责
and you're gonna be responsible for 1,000 San Franciscos.
这就是为什么我们需要取回机器
Which is why we need to get it back.
艾玛总说没人比你更了解奥卡
Emma always said no one knew the ORCA better than you.
那东西就不该存在
It shouldn't even exist.
即便如此 马克
That may be, Mark.
但它已落入坏人手里
But it's fallen into the wrong hands.
现在 奥卡是唯一的
And right now, the ORCA is the only thing
能让艾玛和麦蒂森活着的保命符
keeping Emma and Madison alive.
马克 我们知道你很受伤
Mark, we know you're hurting.
但如果我们找到奥卡 就能找到你的家人
But if we find the ORCA, we'll find your family.
我保证
I promise.
最后一次和艾玛通话实在什么时候？
When was the last time you spoke to Emma?
大约三年前
About three years ago.
旧金山事件后
After San Francisco,
我们回到了波士顿
we went back home to Boston.
试图修补残破的家庭
Tried to put the pieces back together.
艾玛治疗的方法是加倍努力拯救世界
Emma dealt with it by doubling down on saving the world
我开始酗酒
and I started drinking.
我无法告诉你我有多么恨自己
I can't tell you how much I hated myself
因为让麦蒂森就这样看着我
for letting Maddie see me that way.
呃 介意我打个岔吗
Uh, you mind if we cut in here?
你们一定向看看这个
It's just, you're gonna wanna see this.
艾玛结合了生物声学
Emma combined the bioacoustics
混合了不同的泰坦 创造了奥卡讯号
of different Titans to create the ORCA's signal.
一种基线频率
A sort of baseline frequency
能让所有巨兽都回应
that all the creatures respond to.
吸引他们 吓跑他们
Attracting them, repelling them,
甚至有时能让他们平静下来
even at times calming them down.
真的非常了不起
It's pretty remarkable actually.
问题是我们还不知道她混合了
The problem is we don't know
哪些泰坦的频率
which Titans she combined.
但如果你能识别出这些频率
But if you can identify those frequencies,
我们就能跟踪奥卡讯号
we'll be able to track the ORCA
找到艾玛和麦蒂森
and find Emma and Madison.
天哪
Jesus
到底有多少种巨兽啊？
How many of these things are there?
在哥斯拉之后有17只 还在一直增加
Seventeen and counting after Gojira.
17只？
Seventeen?
其中大部分在休眠
Most of them were discovered in deep hibernation.
其他的被封锁了
While others we've contained
在全球的顶级秘密基地
at top secret sites around the globe.
柬埔寨 墨西哥 骷髅岛
Cambodia, Mexico, Skull Island.
我们甚至在怀俄明州找到了一只
We even found one in Wyoming.
他们无处不在
They're everywhere.
为什么你们不杀了他们？
Why don't you kill 'em?
政府想这么做
The government wants to.
但艾玛和我相信有些巨兽是无害的
But Emma and I believe some are benevolent.
不要自欺欺人了
Don't kid yourself.
呃 嘿 看 我们到了
Uh... Hey, look at that. We're here.
暴徒堡
Castle Bravo,
这里是猛禽一号 请求进入
this is Raptor One. On direct approach.
暴徒堡
帝王组织前哨54号基地
百慕大群岛
猛禽一号 准许降落
Raptor One, you are cleared
请至四号升降台
for assisted descent to pad four.
传感器设置为三米
Sensors set for three meters.
开始朝底层下降
Beginning sub-surface descent.
这是新设施
This is new.
是的 我们称之为暴徒堡
Yeah, we call it Castle Bravo.
我们的新旗舰设备
Our new flagship facility
建在哥斯拉的地盘上 以便于研究和追踪
built to track and study Godzilla on his own turf.
我以为他失踪了
I thought he was missing.
好吧 只有你不知道它的行踪
Well, only if you don't know where to look.
如你们所知 大约在早上七点
As you know, at approximately 0700 hours,
我们位于中国云南热带雨林的
our containment site
封锁基地被袭击了
in China's Yunnan Rainforest was raided.
代号摩斯拉的物种逃脱
The specimen, code name Mothra, escaped.
随后在附近的瀑布后方结茧
Only to cocoon itself later under a nearby waterfall.
在艾玛拉塞尔博士
While Doctor Emma Russell
和她的女儿麦蒂森被劫持的时候
and her daughter Madison were taken hostage.
这是幕后男猪脚 艾伦乔纳
This is the man responsible, Alan Jonah.
一名前应该陆军上校 后来成了生态恐怖分子
A former British army colonel turned ecoterrorist.
痴迷与重建自然法则
Obsessed with restoring natural order.
为了资助他的行动
And to fund his operations,
他开始在全新而危险的黑市走私
he began trafficking in a new and dangerous market.
泰坦的DNA
Titan DNA.
这种大蝴蝶能做什么？
What the hell is someone gonna do with a giant worm?
你他妈在逗我 马丁内斯？
Are you kidding, Martinez?
啥都能干
What can't you do with it?
制药 生物武器 食物
Pharmaceuticals, bioweapons, food...
天哪 这星球上没有任何一个国家或公司
Hell, there isn't a country or a company on the planet
不想插手这些大家伙
that doesn't wanna get its hands on one of these suckers.
请记住 这只是一只幼虫
And remember, this is just a larva.
还是个小宝宝
That's a baby.
结茧之后
After it cocoons,
她会羽化成其他东西
something else is gonna crawl out.
更大更凶残的东西
Something bigger, meaner...
-这还说不定呢 不是吗 里克老头？ -哦 是吗?
- We don't know that, Rick. - Oh, yeah?
等着瞧吧 小陈 你还太年轻了
Just wait for it, Chen.
我们的情报显示 乔纳想要
Our intel indicates that Jonah wants
活捉这个巨兽
to capture this specimen.
活捉
Alive.
这意味他的雇佣兵紧随在后
Which means that he and his mercs won't be far behind.
凌晨五点我们将发起联合行动
At 0500, we'll ship out to launch a joint operation...
我不是故意打断
I wouldn't bother.
啥?
Excuse me?
听起来想声东击西
Sounds like a duck hunt to me.
呃 马克 你咋不能让福斯特上校先说完呢
Uh, Mark, why don't we let Colonel Foster finish...
一个诱饵 调虎离山
A decoy. A diversion.
反正他们已经有了艾玛和奥卡音频
Look, they've already got Emma and the ORCA.
如果他们已经掌握了 他们何必只为一只奔波
Why would they want just this one when they've got the keys
回到你的魔法王国？
to your entire magic kingdom of horrors back here?
我觉得他们是想你们去追摩斯拉
I think that they want you to go after this Mothra
这样他们就能专注于真正的目标
so they can go after a real prize.
更大的巨兽
Something bigger.
行吧
Right.
马克
Mark,
这不是他们抓走了第一只巨兽
this is not the first specimen they've captured.
他们经验老道
They know what they are doing.
这不仅关系到巨兽
That's not just a specimen.
别忘了还有我的前妻和女儿
I've got an ex-wife and a daughter out there,in case you forgot.
不 没人会忘记 马克
No. No one has forgotten that, Mark,
但是   呃 还是得提醒你
but, uh, to remind you,
你被带来这里
you were brought on here
是为了帮助跟踪奥卡并给我们建议
to help track the ORCA, and to advise us...
我建议你们杀掉这些怪兽 所有的怪兽
I advise you to kill these things. All of 'em.
特别是哥斯拉
Especially him.
你们想确定这些东西不落入坏人手里？
You wanna make sure these things don't fall into the wrong hands?
你们杀了他们 那奥卡就没用了
You kill them and the ORCA's useless.
老弟 你老婆艾玛不会希望是这样的
Emma wouldn't have wanted that.
即便是为了救她的命
Even to save her life.
好吧 这不是第一次了
Well, it wouldn't be the first time
她把工作放在自己之前
Emma put all of this before herself
甚至是家庭 不是吗？
or her family, would it?
这老哥挺讨厌泰坦呀
Dude hates Titans.
是的 如果你是他 你也会的
Yeah, well, you would too, if you were him.
32号基地  这里是猛禽五号
Outpost 32, this is Raptor Five,
载运增援和补给物品
on approach with reinforcements and supplies.
请求允许降落
Requesting permission to land.
芹泽要求所有基地都处于高度戒备状态
Serizawa has all sites on high alert,
所以请发送紧急代码
so transmitting emergency codes now.
收到 猛禽五号
Copy that, Raptor Five.
密码正确 欢迎返航
Codes are good. Nice to have you back.
南 极 洲
帝王组织前哨32号基地
上
Go.
很高兴见到你们
It's good to see ya.
-需要帮忙卸货吗 -谢了 我们自己可以
- Need a hand with offload? - No, we're good
我们要把它放在五号湾
We're gonna put it over at bay five.
-跟着我  -回去吧 嘿 嘿
- Follow me  - Go back up  Hey, hey
别管了 我们走吧
Leave them, let's go
我害怕
I'm scared.
我知道 我也怕
I know. Me, too.
好了
Okay.
我们走吧
Let's go.
目视前方
Eyes straight ahead.
深呼吸
Deep breaths.
就像我们之前说的那样
Just like we talked about.
呃
Hmm.
圣母玛丽亚呀
Mother of God.
圣母可没有这东西
She had nothing to do with this.
零号怪兽
Monster Zero.
有幸存者吗？
Any survivors?
没有 他们想送出紧急信号
No. They tried to launch an emergency beacon,
但我们及时切断了
but we cut them off in time.
他们迟早会发现的
They'll figure it out.
开始打洞
Fire up the drills.
东西备齐了吗
Do you have everything you need?
好了
Good.
很好 那我们开始吧
Well, let's get started.
再远点
Further.
我们现在面临着来自灰熊的严峻形势
We have a grizzly situation up here in the attic.
来吧 安德鲁  安德鲁
Come on, Andrew. Andrew.
我来吃你的马啦
I've come to eat your horses.
不 你不能吃我的马
No, you can't eat my horses...
那不是
That's not...
停
Stop.
你们看
Look.
有入侵者 抓住她  抓住她
- An intruder  Get her  - Get her
-抓住她 抓住她 -不 别抓我
- Get her  Get her  - No, don't get me
安德鲁 麦蒂森 抓住她
Andrew, Madison  Get her
-抓住她 -灰熊之吻
- Get her  - Bear kisses.
灰熊之吻
Bear kisses
所有人员进入战斗位置
All personnel, report to battle stations. Code red.
All personnel, report to battle stations.
-红色警戒 -至少60节
- Code red. - At least 60 knots.
这不是演习
This is not a drill.
所有人员进入战斗位置
All personnel, report to battle stations.
红色警戒
Code red.
发生了什么？
What's happening?
出了点问题
Something's wrong.
他之前从未如此接近过
He's never been this close before.
-他是谁？ -你说呢？
- Who's he? - Who do you think?
他在摧毁我们的无人机
He's taking out our observation drones.
行进方向？
Trajectory?
直奔我们来了 200米迫近中
Straight at us  1,200 meters and closing.
G小队 巴恩斯 马丁内斯 亨德里克斯
G-Team. Barnes, Martinez, Hendricks,
立即进入远端武器控制台
I want you on those CROWS now
你们听清楚老大的话了吧 麻溜的
You heard boss lady  Let's move
斯坦顿博士 你有他的生物声学吗？
Doctor Stanton. Do you have his bioacoustics?
生物声学马上来
Acoustics coming up
好了 他越来越近了 距离800米
Okay, he's closing. We're at 800 meters
行进路线飘忽不定
Its movements are erratic.
心跳和呼吸加速了
Heart and breathing elevated.
是的 他肯定对什么事很不爽
Yeah, he's definitely not happy about something.
他们怎么得到这些的？
How are they getting all this?
艾玛分离出哥斯拉生物声学
Emma isolated Godzilla's bioacoustics.
让我们能追踪他
It allows us to track him.
甚至读取它的生命指数
Even to get his vitals.
他绕着我们游 迫近中 200米
Circling now, closing in, 200 meters.
上校
Colonel
所有人就位 武器准备
All teams in position, weapons hot,
等我下令开火
ready to engage on my command.
来吧 来吧 来吧
Come on, come on, come on.
稳住
Hold your fire.
我们不知道他会不会攻击
We don't know he'll attack.
如果你们继续用枪指着他的话
He will if you keep those guns on him.
现在我比任何人都想他死
Now I want him dead more than anybody,
但如果你们没有胜算
but unless this is a fight that you know that you can win,
看在上帝的面子上 解除装备
for God's sake, stand down.
解除装备
Stand down.
你不是认真的吧
You can't be serious.
我是认真的
I am.
解除戒备
Stand down.
再说一遍 收起武器
I say again, safe your weapons.
不要开火
Do not engage.
听
Listen.
他的心跳放缓了
His heart rate, it's slowing.
打开防护罩
Open the shields.
哦 当然 让我们带她进来喝杯啤酒吧
Oh, yeah, sure. Let's bring him in for a beer.
你脑袋进水了？
You out of your goddamn mind?
让他知道我们不是威胁
Let him know we're not a threat.
打开防护罩
Open the shields.
打开吧
Do it.
嘿 那光闪闪是咋回事
Hey, what's with the light show?
他在向我们示威
It's an intimidation display.
就像大猩猩捶胸顿足
Like a gorilla pounding his chest.
说真的 我们都快
Consider us very
被闪尿了
intimidated.
我觉得他的目标不是我们
I don't think it's for us.
伙计 你在干嘛？
What are you doing, dude?
哦 刚才真是有趣
Well, that was interesting.
我的天
Jesus
我们现在能关防护罩了吗
Can we maybe close the shield now?
给我看看他的地盘线路
Show me his territorial routes.
啥？咋了？
What? Why?
因为我想开发新的航行线路   赶紧给我看
Because I wanna start a boat tour. Just show me.
好的 马上
Okay. Coming up.
能告诉我们你在找什么吗
You care to tell us what you're looking for?
当动物离开狩猎场时
When an animal leaves its hunting ground,
通常是因为它收到某些东西的威胁了
it's usually because it's threatened by something.
快做路径预测图
Run a course projection.
我们要去追他
We gotta go after him.
他正在找一些东西
He's looking for something out there.
那可能是奥卡
It could be the ORCA.
斯坦顿博士 预测结果是什么？
Doctor Stanton, what's your projection?
所有可能路径都通往同一个地方
All paths have him landing in the same place.
南极洲
Antarctica.
那就好
Good, then.
我的意思是 我们走吧我们去找他吧 让我们
I mean, let's go  Let's go find him. Let's...
等等 南极洲有什么？
Wait, what's in Antarctica?
巴恩斯
Barnes,
联系亚果号
contact the Argo.
好的 长官
Yes, ma'am.
阿戈号航空母舰
帝王组织指挥舰
这个地方的物体
The specimen at this site
一直被官方保密未登录
has been kept entirely off-book.
而且最近才出土
And since it's a more recent discovery,
我们数据有限
our data is limited.
但他似乎是另一个顶级掠食者
But it seems to be another apex predator.
艾玛叫他零号巨兽
Emma called it Monster Zero.
他可能是哥斯拉的劲敌
It may have been a rival alpha to Godzilla.
争夺其它泰坦巨兽的统治地位
Battling for dominance over the other Titans.
陈博士？
Doctor Chen?
我一直在努力查找几千年来的
I've been scouring through thousands of years
神话和传说
of myths and legends.
但人们好像害怕到不敢
But it's almost as if people were scared
去记录下他们
to even write about it.
仿佛他本该被遗忘
As if it was meant to be forgotten.
不好意思打断一下
Sorry, I hate to crash a party,
我得到了一些坏消息
but I got some bad news.
你可以直接说消息 反正都是坏的
You could just say news. It's always bad.
我们跟丢了哥斯拉
We lost Godzilla.
他在委内瑞拉附近失踪了
He dropped off the scan near Venezuela.
消失了？
Dropped off?
我不得不说 布鲁克斯博士是对的
I'm telling you, Doctor Brooks was right.
地球是空心的
It's a Hollow Earth.
所以他才能迅速移动
That's how he moves around so fast
用像虫洞一样的水下隧道
using these underwater tunnels like wormholes.
四处游走
Just zippin' around.
大家注意
Everyone look sharp.
我们正在接近基地
We're approaching the base.
-他们来了 -拖住他们
- They're here. - Keep 'em busy.
发动反动力 搬出去
Launch reaction force. Move out
好了 各位  出发吧
All right, gents  Got the green light
如果乔纳
If Jonah is looking
想要窃取基因样本
to extract genetic samples
他们将去生物实验室
they'll be here in the bio labs.
好了 两分钟
All right, two minutes
检查你们的设备 靠门站好
Check your equipment, stand by the door.
艾什 你动作快点
Come on, Ash. Make it snappy.
-引爆器已连接 -我们走吧
- Detonator ready. - Let's go.
走吧 麦蒂
Come on, Maddie.
快走 快走
Move  Move
记住 睁大眼睛 里面有自己人
Remember, eyes wide. We got friendlies in here.
进入二号隧道
Move to tunnel two.
提供掩护
Stay on overwatch.
收到 老大
Roger that, Chief.
伏击 伏击
Ambush  Ambush
小队遇到袭击 伤亡严重
Team under fire  360 ambush
我们正在遭受重创
We're taking heavy losses.
向右突破
Break right
停火 停火
Hold your fire  Hold your fire
有自己人
We got friendlies
不
No
马克？
Mark?
去帮巴恩斯 我去追他
Get down there and help Barnes. I'm going after him.
收到
Roger that.
各位 我收到了心电图
Hey, guys. I'm getting an EKG reading.
艾玛？
Emma?
麦蒂？
Maddie
一号 快走
Number one, let's go.
巴恩斯 我是福斯特
Barnes, this is Foster.
我已锁定目标 重复 我已锁定目标
I've got eyes on the target. Repeat, eyes on the target.
让她们走
Let 'em go
-艾什  -爸
- Ash  - Dad
-马克  -艾玛 麦迪森 我们走
- Mark. - Emma, Madison, let's go.
爸爸
Dad.
我们走
Let's go.
-艾玛 麦蒂 我们走  -爸爸?
- Emma, Maddie, come on. - Daddy?
麦迪森 朝我这来
Madison, walk to me.
过来吧 来吧 亲爱的
Walk to me now. Come on, honey.
巴恩斯 有两个人质 已击杀一个目标
Barnes, I've got two hostages, one target down.
-快点 麦蒂 -我无法锁定目标
- Now  Come on, Maddie. - I do not have a shot.
重复 我无法锁定目标
Repeat, I do not have a shot.
艾玛 你在干嘛？我们走吧 快
Emma, what are you doing? Let's go. Come on
-爸  -麦蒂
- Dad. - Maddie.
爸爸
Dad.
麦迪森
Madison.
搞什么?
What the hell?
对不起
I'm sorry.
快跑
Run.
麦蒂
Maddie
爸爸
Dad
快 快
Move, move
-福斯特  -快离开那 快
- Foster  - Get out of the way
-我们走吧  -坚持住 快
- Let's go  - Hang on  Move
很德里克斯 拉把手
Hendricks, on the double
-上校 我抓住你了  -抓住她的腿
- I got you, Colonel  - Get her legs
我们必须走了
We gotta go
该死的
Damn it
马丁内斯 福斯特 我们走
Martinez, Foster, let's go
快 快  动起来
Move, move  Come on
快 我们走  快进去
Come on, let's go  Strap in
没时间一项项检查了  检查间隙是否清楚
No checklist this time. Check clearance right.
清楚
Clear right.
-爸爸来这做什么? -我不知道 亲爱的
- What is Dad doing here? - I don't know, honey.
我们走吧
Let's go.
我们不能丢下他
We can't leave him.
你在等什么?
What are you waiting for?
快唤醒他
Wake it up.
我们走  快
Let's go  Move it
你他妈在逗我
You gotta be fucking kidding.
撤退  撤退
Fall back  Fall back
上直升机
Get to the chopper
快 快 快
Go, go, go
开火
Open fire
我们将以最大转速垂直齐飞
We'll do an emergency vertical take-off at max RPM.
二号螺旋桨仍在加速
Number two's still speeding up.
噢 该死
Oh, shit.
猛禽一号呼叫亚果号
This is Raptor One to Argo.
请求立即撤退
Requesting immediate urgent extract.
重复 紧急撤退
Again, I say urgent extract.
格里芬 快让我们离开这鬼地方
Griffin, get us the hell out of here
麦迪森
Madison
麦迪森 不
Madison, no
-放手吧  -不 不 不
- You need to let go of it  - No  No  No
-麦迪森  -麦迪森 松手
- Madison  - Maddie  Let go
不
No
亚果号 这里是猛禽一号 我们收到了攻击
Argo, this is Raptor One. We've been hit.
所有系统失效
All systems are down.
小心
Look out
大伙抓紧了
Everybody, hold on
马克
Mark
大家快出去 我们走
Everybody, clear out. Let's go
走 走 走
Go  Go
-马克  -我被卡住了
- Mark  - I'm stuck.
你还好吧?
Are you all right?
搞定了  我搞定了  快走
Got it  I got it. Go, go
卫星上有什么踪影吗?
Anything on the satellites?
潜艇看到哥斯拉朝阿根廷移动
Subs have Godzilla hauling ass off Argentina.
我们在巴西的热带风暴中跟丢了零号巨兽
We lost Monster Zero in a tropical storm over Brazil.
扫描整个南半球
Scanning the entire Southern Hemisphere.
目前为止一无所获
So far, nothing.
那就扫描北半球
Then scan the Northern.
好的 好的
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
我知道我看到了什么 山姆
I know what I saw, Sam.
我告诉你 她按下了那个扳机
And I'm telling you, she pulled that trigger.
恕我直言 上校 你看错了
All due respect, Colonel, you saw wrong.
好吗? 她不会这么做
Okay? She wouldn't have done it.
天哪 这屋子里的所有人都是她雇来的
Christ, she recruited pretty much everyone in this room.
也许是乔纳强迫她的 对吗?
Maybe Jonah forced her, right?
也许他用麦迪森挟持她
Maybe he used Madison as leverage.
不 不 肯定是别人
No, no. It had to be someone else.
艾玛
Emma.
是艾玛
It was Emma.
福斯特没看错
Foster saw it right.
是她  没人强迫她
It was her. No one forced her to.
你确定吗？
Are you sure?
首先 她释放了摩斯拉
First, she releases Mothra.
然后是零号巨兽
And now Monster Zero.
有人看出其中的关联吗
Anyone else sensing a pattern here?
有 并且情况不妙
Yes, and not a good one.
她好像要唤醒所有的怪兽
It's as if she is trying to start a mass awakening.
真糟糕 没人警告你们
Well, it's just too bad that no one tried
会有惨剧发生吗？
to warn you that that was gonna happen.
等等 伙计们
Hang on, guys.
她为什么要释放怪兽？
Why the hell would she want to release them?
为什么她会和乔纳合作
And why would she team up with Jonah,
为什么会这样做？
of all people, to do it?
我们会问她的
We'll ask her
等我们找到她
when we find her.
所以我们继续找吧
So, let's keep looking.
哥斯拉的行进路线
Godzilla appears to be following
与艾玛的直升机相同
the same path as Emma's osprey,
越过南美洲朝北到这里
heading north over South America to here.
墨西哥马拉岛的56号基地
Outpost 56 in Isla de Mara, Mexico.
我们将在十分钟内抵达
We touch down there in ten minutes.
那些人怎么办？
What about the people?
什么人?
I'm sorry?
那些人们 在村子里的人们
The people. The people down there in that village
他们不会意识到
that don't realize they're gonna be
他们会成为当天的特餐
the special of the day.
我们派了G小队去疏散
We've sent G-Team to begin an evacuation.
芹泽博士
Doctor Serizawa,
我们在紧急频道上
we have a call on the emergency channel
接到一个来自马拉岛的电话
from Isla de Mara.
接进来
Answer it.
我猜我应该先说
I suppose I should go first.
麦迪森在哪?
Where's Madison?
-她就在我身边 -爸爸 你还好吗?
- She's right here with me. - Dad, are you okay?
麦迪森 你没事吧？
Madison, you all right, hon?
爸
Dad...
对不起
I'm sorry.
你不用道歉
You don't need to be...
没关系 没关系
It's okay. It's okay.
对不起 爸爸
I'm sorry, Dad.
她很好 马克 相信我
She's fine, Mark, trust me.
信任你有点难啊
Trust is a little hard
拉塞尔博士
to come by, Doctor Russell.
特别是在你摆了大家一道之后
Especially after what you pulled.
我知道
I know.
我也能想象你们在想什么
And I can only imagine what you're all thinking.
但如果有其它方法 我也不会出此下策
But if there were any other way to do this, I would.
你要干嘛 艾玛?
Do what, Emma?
我在拯救世界
I'm saving the world.
通过释放怪兽吗？放你的狗屁
But by releasing those things? That doesn't make sense.
尽管看起来不大可能 但确实如此
As impossible as it seems, it does.
听我说 马克
Hear me out, Mark.
在我们失去安德鲁后
After we lost Andrew,
我发誓他的牺牲不会白费
I swore his death would not be in vain.
我会找到答案
That I would find an answer.
关于泰坦回归的原因
A solution to why the Titans were rising.
但当我深入挖掘后
But as I dug deeper,
我意识到他们来这里是有原因的
I realized that they were here for a reason.
尽管这些年来
And that despite all the years
我们努力试图阻止他们
that we spent trying to stop them,
我们从不敢面对真相
we never dared to confront the truth.
什么真相？
Which truth?
数千年来 人类一直霸占地球
Humans have been the dominant species for thousands of years
看看 发生了什么
and look what's happened.
人口过剩
Overpopulation,
污染 战争
pollution, war.
我们担心的大规模灭绝已经开始了
The mass extinction we feared has already begun.
我们正是元凶
And we are the cause.
我们是感染源
We are the infection.
但向所有生物一样
But like all living organisms,
地球使用了防御机制来对抗这种感染
the earth unleashed a fever to fight this infection.
最原始最合法的规则
Its original and rightful rulers,
泰坦巨兽
the Titans.
他们是地球自然防御系统的一部分
They are part of the earth's natural defense system.
用于保护地球 维持平衡
A way to protect the planet, to maintain its balance.
但如果政府封锁 摧毁他们
But if governments are allowed to contain them, destroy them,
或将他们用于战争
or use them for war,
人类的感染只会继续蔓延
the human infection will only continue to spread.
在我们有生之年 我们的星球会灭亡
And within our lifetime, our planet will perish,
我们也将灭绝
and so will we.
除非我们恢复平衡
Unless we restore balance.
如果你这样做会留下什么？
And what's gonna be left, if you do this?
一个被怪物蹂躏的死寂焦土？
A dead, charred world, overrun by monsters?
不是的 斯坦顿博士
No, Doctor Stanton,
恰恰相反
the exact opposite.
就像森林大火能滋润土壤
Just like how a forest fire replenishes the soil
或是火山能创造新的土地
or how a volcano creates new land,
迹象显示 怪兽也能带来如此荣景
we have seen signs that these creatures will do the same.
旧金山 拉斯维加斯 无论泰坦去哪
San Francisco, Las Vegas, wherever the Titans go,
生命力因辐射激发而绽放
life follows, triggered by their radiation.
唯有他们
They are the only thing that can reverse
才能修复我们所造成的破坏
the destruction that we started.
他们是生命延续的唯一保证
They are the only guarantee that life will carry on.
但要实现这点 我必须让他们自由
But for that to happen, we must set them free.
你正在谋杀这个世界
You are murdering the world.
不
No.
即便前路艰辛
Because as difficult as this will be,
我保证人类不会灭绝
I promise humanity will not go extinct.
使用奥卡 我们将回归自然秩序
Using the ORCA, we will return to a natural order.
在被遗忘的秩序中 与泰坦巨兽
A forgotten order, where we coexisted
地球上的第一批神祗 和谐共存
in balance with the Titans.The first gods.
这是条危险的道路
This is a dangerous path.
你意图操纵人类未知的力量
You are meddling with forces beyond our comprehension.
拿几十亿人的性命做赌注
Gambling with the lives of billions
你何尝不是在赌博 芹泽?
And what are you gambling with, Serizawa?
帝王组织已破裂
Monarch is broken.
政府将强制关闭帝王计划
It's on the verge of being shut down by a government
并一致决定消灭这些怪兽
whose only objective is to eradicate the creatures.
如果发生这种情况 我们的希望在哪？
And if that happens, what will our chances be?
你真的是脑子坏掉了
You are out of your goddamn mind
首先 你把我们的女儿置于危险之中
First, you put our daughter's life in danger,
你现在又开始决定世界的命运了
and now you get to decide the fate of the world.
-这是胡闹 艾玛  -我头脑非常清楚
- That's rich, Emma  - I couldn't be more sane,
麦迪森也很坚强
and Madison couldn't be stronger.
在我们失去安德鲁后 我训练她如何自保
After we lost Andrew, I trained her to survive.
至少现在她努力就会有机会
And at least now, she will have a fighting chance.
努力就有机会？你在炖什么毒鸡汤
A fighting chance? Why don't you listen to yourself?
这不仅仅是数学公式 艾玛
It's not all math, Emma.
有的东西你无法控制
Some things, you can't control.
有的事你无法逃避
And there are some things that you can't run from.
这不会让他回到我们身边
This won't bring him back to us.
我只能敦促大家避难吧
I can only urge you all to take refuge.
在过去的60年里
Over the last 60 years,
帝王组织在世界各地准备了底下堡垒
Monarch has prepared bunkers around the world
用以拯救并重启文明
to save and restart civilization.
我建议你们找到它们
I suggest you find them.
臭婊子
That bitch.
还有多久降落
How long until this thing lands?
三分钟
Three minutes.
或许你可以重新考虑一下
You might want to rethink that.
为什么?
Why?
有点不对劲 看下这个
Something's not right. Check this out.
艾玛不在马拉岛
Emma's not at Isla de Mara.
我的意思是信号太弱 根本不在当地
I mean, the signal's too weak to be local.
她正在用我们的卫星传输信号
She's bouncing it off our satellites.
他们肯定藏在某个旧碉堡里
They must be holed up in one of our old bunkers.
她可能无处不在
She could be anywhere.
那是什么？
What is that?
该死的 我的天 她把封锁系统关了
Oh, Jesus  She shut down the containment system.
我们有多少时间
How much time do we have?
解除封锁并骇入扩音系统
Containment system bypassed. We're patched in.
-嗯  -准备播放奥卡
- Hmm. - Ready to broadcast the ORCA.
博士?
Doctor?
妈 不要
Mom, don't
抱歉 所以一个小孩来指点江山了?
I'm sorry, did a child just tell you what to do?
也许爸爸是对的  也许不该这样
Maybe Dad is right. Maybe this isn't the way.
那好吧 拉塞尔博士
By all means, Doctor Russell,
让我们重新考虑整个计划
let's reconsider our entire plan.
特别是在通知了你的朋友后
Especially after telling your friends about it.
麦迪森 我们已经谈过这个了
Madison, we talked about this.
不 你说你会帮助大家
No, you said you were gonna help people,
你会先让他们找到庇护所
that you would let them find shelter.
我们没时间了
We don't have time for this
你真觉得这会很容易吗
Did you really think this was gonna be easy?
不痛不痒？ 你是这么告诉她的？
Painless? Is that what you told her?
别把她扯进来
Leave her out of this.
为什么？难道不是你把她扯进来的？
Why? You're the one who pulled her into it.
麦迪森 告诉我 你妈是怎么说服你的
Madison, tell me, what exactly did Mommy sell you on?
乌托邦的故事？
Some grand utopia?
人与巨兽和谐共存？
Man and monster, living together
一起快乐生活？
in blissful harmony?
先生 他们试图防堵我们
Sir, they're attempting to lock us out.
再不动手来不及了
It's now or never.
艾玛 你来找我 告诉我这是你的计划
Emma, you came to me. This is your plan.
我们都想拯救地球
We both want to save the planet,
但如果不彻底执行
but everything is going to die
所有人都得死
if we don't see it through.
拜托 至少让他们安全逃离
Please, at least let them get to safety.
女士 我们的机窗口正在关闭
Ma'am, our window's closing.
妈
Mom...
对不起 麦迪森
I'm sorry, Madison.
这比你我更重要
This is bigger than just you and me.
让他们慢慢来 别挤
Tell them to slow it down
让他们站回去
Tell them to stand back
走开 别挡道
Move  Get out of the way
疏散人群
Clear, men
这个有什么响亮的称号吗
You got a catchy name for this one?
当地传说称其为
Local legends call it
炎魔拉顿
Rodan, the fire demon.
听起来真是让人欣慰啊
That's comforting.
伙计们？
Guys?
你们记得那热带风暴吗？
You remember that tropical storm
害我们追丢零号巨兽的那个
where we lost Monster Zero?
它正在改变方向 并且 额
It's changing direction and, uh,
猜猜它现在朝哪去
guess where it's headed now.
这不可能
That's not possible.
没有风暴能移动的这么快
No storm moves that fast.
除非那不是风暴
Unless it's not a storm.
-我的天  -我们需要时间
- Oh, man  - We need time
来完成疏散
to finish the evacuation.
好吧 那你们最好快点
Well, then you'd better hurry,
因为它正在快速接近
'cause it's closing in fast.
芹泽 这不是巧合
Serizawa, it's not a coincidence
零号朝这来了
that Monster Zero thing is headed here.
他在响应大火鸟的呼叫
It's reacting to Big Bird's cries.
这意味着他不是来觅食 干架
That means it's coming for food, a fight, or a...
某些更亲密的需求
Something more intimate.
你有什么建议?
What do you suggest?
所有战机
All fighters,
自由开火
weapons free.
哦 我想我们引起了他的注意
Oh, I think we got his attention.
大家系好安全带
Everyone strap in.
全体机队 跟着我们
All ships, follow our lead.
不
No
拜托 不要
Please  Wait
不会没事的
It's gonna be okay
坚持住 孩子
Hang on, kid
亚果号呼叫黄金中队
Argo to Gold Squadron.
把大火鸡引进陆地
Let's lure this turkey away from the mainland
朝零号飞去
straight to Monster Zero.
预计两分钟抵达
ETA two minutes
黄金中队 在后方直接开战
Gold Squadron, engage on our six.
收到 开始倒计时
Copy. Start the clock.
大火鸟在高处九点钟方向
Bogey. Nine o'clock high
达斯特223
Duster 223.
他在你后面 快闪开
Get out of there. He's on your tail  Get out of there
眼镜蛇座机坠毁
Cobra's Raptor is off the team
预计六十秒后与零号接触
ETA to Monster Zero, 60 seconds
猛禽37
Raptor 37.
大火鸟在你正后方
Bogey coming up on your six.
我在失去控制
I'm losing control here.
I'm losing control
机队全灭
We lost the squadron
30秒后与怪兽零号交汇
ETA to Monster Zero, 30 seconds
10秒
Ten seconds
下潜 下潜
Dive  Dive
天啊 他们在自相残杀
Jesus, they're killing each other.
求救求救猛禽一号呼叫亚果
Mayday, mayday  This is Raptor One to Argo.
亚果 收到了吗
Argo, do you read?
收到 情况如何
Copy, Raptor One. What's your status?
我们快挂了
We're screwed, that's what.
有孩子在飞机上
And we got kids on board.
我们需要立即进行空中救援
We're gonna need immediate mid-air retrieval.
锁定他们的位置 并准备停机坪
Lock on to their position, and prepare the hangar
准备紧急着陆
for an emergency landing.
停机坪舱门没有回应
Hangar doors are unresponsive.
-手动控制呢？ -卡住了
- Manual override? - They're stuck
行了 停机坪在哪?
All right, which way to the hangar?
我带你去
I can show you.
其他人呢?
Anybody else?
我知道在哪 我 来吧
I know the way. I... Come on
希望你的工具给力
Hope you got a big wrench.
什么问题?
What's the problem?
液压系统卡住了
Hydraulics systems are jammed
我正尝试跨接启动电源
I'm trying to jump-start power.
但情况不妙
It's not looking good.
是海军上将滕兹
It's Admiral Stenz.
上将
Admiral.
博士 芹泽 福斯特上校
Doctor Serizawa, Colonel Foster.
我需要你和你的部队立即撤退
I need you and your forces to immediately disengage
撤回至安全距离
and withdraw to a safe distance.
上将 我不明白
Admiral, I don't understand.
我们一直在开发新武器
We have been developing a prototype for a new weapon.
水中氧气破坏剂
An oxygen destroyer.
能消灭两公里范围内
Designed to exterminate all life forms
所有的生命体
within a two-mile radius.
运气好的话 能杀死这些巨兽
With any luck, it will kill these things
这场噩梦将结束
and this nightmare will finally be over.
上将 我们必须对哥斯拉有信心
Admiral, we must keep our faith in Gojira.
对不起博士 你们机会了
I'm sorry, Doctor. You had your chance.
导弹已经在路上了
The missile is already on its way.
愿上帝垂怜我们
May God have mercy on us all.
他没说谎
He's not lying.
导弹全速袭来
It's coming in hot.
亚果 现在就得打开舱门
Argo, you gotta get those bay doors open now
叫救护和消防队就位
Have the crash and fire crews ready.
你特么在做什么
What the hell do you think you're doing?
小心
Look out
抓紧了
Hold on
加油 格里夫 加油
Come on, Griff  Come on
撞他 撞他
Hit it  Hit it
飞机就得这么开 格里夫
That's what I'm talking about, Griff
大家还好吗？
Everybody okay?
到停机坪后面去
Get over to the back of the hangar.
大家往这走 这里这里
We're all gonna head this way. This way. This way.
谢谢你载我一程
Thanks for the lift
走  快走
Go  Go
天啊
Oh, God
我们快离开这
We're getting out of here.
军方发射了新武器
The military launched a weapon.
会杀死他们两
It's gonna kill 'em both.
恩 这主意不错
Well, that's not the worst idea.
十
Ten,
九
nine,
八
eight,
七
seven...
三 二
...three, two...
天
Jesus.
斯坦顿博士 你们找到哥斯拉的位置吗
Doctor Stanton, can you locate Gojira?
是的 我发现了些东西
Yeah. I got something.
他的生命指数在衰减 辐射值在直线下降
His vitals are fading. Radiation levels plummeting.
加油 大家伙 干他
Come on, big guy. Fight it.
他死了
He's gone.
马克 你的愿望达成了
Looks like you got your wish, Mark.
我以为我们是逐次释放他们
I thought we were going to release them gradually.
一次一个
One at a time.
这不是我做的
I'm not the one doing this.
吾皇万岁
Long live the king.
你才是怪兽
You're a monster.
魔 斯 拉 蚕 茧 基 地
暴徒堡 这里是
Castle Bravo, this is
中国云南热带雨林
封锁小组莫苏拉 能收到吗
Containment Team Mosura. Do you read? Over.
暴徒堡这里是封锁小队
Castle Bravo, this is Containment Team.
啥?
Anything?
布鲁克斯博士
Dr. Brooks.
我们是去了与亚果号的联系
We've lost contact with the Argo,
还有暴徒堡和其他基地
Castle Bravo and the other containment sites.
吴哥窟 骷髅岛 石山
Angkor Wat, Skull Island, Stone Mountain.
所有的泰坦巨兽都逃脱了
All the Titans, they're escaping.
重复 这可能是我们最后的通讯
Repeat, this may be our last comm.
等等 等等
Wait, wait, wait.
这是 这是他
It's... It's him.
这是他造成的
He's the one doing this.
他们在回应他的号召
They're responding to his call.
天啊  凌博士在哪?
Oh, God  Where's Doctor Ling?
她在外面
She's outside.
凌博士 我们失去了与帝王组织的联络
Doctor Ling  We've lost contact with Monarch.
凌博士?
Doctor Ling?
-麦迪森 等等  -离我远点
- Madison, wait  - Get away from me
听着 我知道事情还没结束
Look, I know things haven't gone
情况不如预期 但我可以补救
exactly according to plan, but I can fix this.
不如预期?
According to plan?
你说你会小心的
You said that you were gonna be careful.
你一次释放一个
That you'd release them one at a time,
你会恢复自然的平衡
that you would restore balance
政府将要接管帝王组织
They were gonna take over Monarch
并杀光泰坦 我别无选择
and kill the Titans. I didn't have a choice.
放狗屁
Bullshit
你说我们这么做是为了安德鲁
You said we were doing this for Andrew.
你真觉得他会想要这样吗
Do you really think he would've wanted this?
我想也是
Exactly.
麦迪森
Madison
有头绪吗?
Any luck?
没有
No.
不管艾玛用什么做出这个音频
Whatever Emma used to create the ORCA signal,
都是我没听过的
I've never heard it.
你怎么样?
How are you doing?
你说啥?
How's that?
"神话是我们的指南针 "
"Myth is our compass."
这是我母亲常说的
It's something my mom used to say.
她相信我们关于怪兽和龙的故事
She believed our stories about monsters and dragons
能帮助我们找到泰坦
could help us find the Titans
并恢复我们与自然的连接
and restore our connection to nature.
等等 你母亲?
Wait, your mother?
你是第二代帝王组织成员？
You're second-generation Monarch?
第三代
Third.
这是家族遗传
It runs in the family.
难以置信
That's incredible.
我想你家人不会有什么屠龙秘方吧？
I don't suppose your family has any tips on slaying dragons, do they?
屠龙是西方的概念
Slaying dragons is a Western concept.
在东方 龙是神
In the East, they are sacred.
这些神兽会带来智慧和力量
Divine creatures who brought wisdom, strength,
甚至是救赎
even redemption.
这操蛋的水中氧气破坏剂
This oxygen destroyer,
为什么对零号没用
why wasn't Monster Zero affected?
我不是科学家
I mean, I'm no scientist,
但肯定
but I think it has something to do
和他的头能再生有关
with his goddamn head growing back.
好吧我之前从未见过这种特异功能
Well, I've never seen anything like it.
违反所有已知的自然法则
It violates everything we know about the natural order.
除非他不是自然的一部分
Unless he's not part of the natural order.
你的意思是?
What do you mean?
我拼凑出这些资讯
I was able to piece this together.
他看起来好面熟啊
Well, he looks vaguely familiar.
这讲述了一条伟大的龙
It tells of a great dragon
从星空掉落凡间
who fell from the stars.
一种九头蛇圈起的风暴吞噬了人来和终神
A Hydra whose storm swallowed both men and gods alike.
什么 你的意思是外星生物?
What, you mean an alien?
是的 他不属于我们自然界
Yes. He's not part of our natural order.
他本不该在此
And he's not meant to be here.
冒牌的王者
A false king.
外来物种
An invasive species.
这可以解释他为什么能卷起大风暴
That could explain how he's creating these massive storms
对其他泰坦巨兽产生影响
and the effect he's having on the other Titans.
似乎是随他心情
It's almost like he's reshaping the planet
重新打造地球
to his own liking.
这些传奇 怎么称呼他
These legends, what did they call him?
基多拉 三头六臂的王者
Ghidorah. "The one who is many."
基什么?
Ghi-what?
她说 "娘炮 "
She said, "Gonorrhea."
-谁? -基多拉
- Huh? - Ghidorah
芹泽博士 我们正在接近暴徒堡
Doctor Serizawa, we're approaching Castle Bravo,
但你应该看看这个
but there's something you should see.
我猜你没有邀请访客
I'm guessing you weren't expecting these guys.
莫斯科 伦敦 华盛顿特区
Moscow, London, Washington, D.C.,
全都遭受攻击
all under attack.
泰坦巨兽在每个大陆
On every continent, the Titans are triggering
引发地震 野火 海啸
earthquakes, wildfires, tsunamis,
以及我们尚未定名的大灾难
and disasters we don't even have names for yet.
如同以往
Now as before, we have been trying to lure
我们试图用和物质引诱怪兽
the creatures with nuclear materials,
但这次他们完全不为所动
but they are not taking the bait this time.
他们的行为变得毫无章法
Their behavior has become random.
难以预测
Erratic.
随着战线拉长 兵力透支
And with our forces spread desperately thin
怪兽们在全球畅行无阻
and these things roaming the globe unimpeded,
我们的选择和时间
we are running out of options
也越来越少
and time.
抱歉 你们有要补充的吗?
Excuse me, do you have something to add?
是的 你错了
Yeah. You're wrong.
他们的行为既非毫无章法 更非难以预测
Their behavior is not random or erratic.
允许我插句嘴 先生
If I may, sir.
听起来虽然很神神道道
As amazing as this sounds,
但他们是集体动员 在狩猎
they're moving like a pack. They're hunting.
所有动物 从野狼到虎鲸
All packs, from wolves to killer whales,
他们都听命于一个领袖
they all respond directly to an alpha.
而基多拉是新霸主
And this Ghidorah is the new alpha.
其它怪兽只是听命行事
And all the other creatures are just doing his bidding.
他们是他意志的延伸
They're an extension of him.
如果阻止了他 就阻止了所有巨兽
We stop him, we stop them all.
有其他巨兽
Is there another creature
能和他匹敌吗?
that might stand a chance against him?
没有
No.
基多拉和哥斯拉的敌对关系既古老又独特
Ghidorah and Gojira's rivalry was ancient and unique.
好吧 所以我们杀了个唯一可能
Right, so we killed our best shot
能打败这家伙的打手？
at beating this thing?
乔纳 你没搞懂 这改变一切
Jonah, you don't get it. This changes everything.
哥斯拉死后
With Godzilla gone,
零号不会领导各巨兽
Monster Zero isn't using the Titans
重建地球
to restore the planet.
他会利用他们来摧毁世界
He is using them to destroy it.
这不是共存 这是毁灭
This isn't coexistence. This is extinction.
听着 当你舒舒服服坐在实验室时
Listen, while you were sitting comfortably
我们花数十年
in some laboratory,
打了无数场肮脏的战争
we've been fighting for decades in one dirty war after another.
我亲眼见过人性
I've seen human nature firsthand
而我在这告诉你
and I'm here to tell you
一切不会变更好
that it doesn't get any better.
只会越来越糟
It just gets worse.
我很抱歉零号怪兽
So, I'm sorry that Monster Zero
不如预期
isn't exactly what we were expecting.
但我们打开了潘多拉宝盒
But we opened Pandora's Box and there's no closing it now.
已无退路  或许还有其他方法呢？
Maybe there is.
哦 别傻了
Oh, don't be stupid.
如果再广播 只会暴露我们的位置
You broadcast again, and you will expose us all.
这些生物像鲸鱼一样沟通 好吧?
These creatures communicate like whales, okay?
他们可听到数千英里的声呐
They can hear sonar for thousands of miles,
所以我们派出小队
so let's send a team.
从芬威球场广播奥卡
Let's broadcast the ORCA from Fenway.
那距离这里很近
It's just a few miles from here.
利用体育场来放大信号
I could use the stadium to amplify a signal
这也许能阻止攻击
that might stop these attacks.
城市已进行疏散 会很安全
The city's already being evacuated, so it'll be safe.
然后呢？
And then what?
我会查处零号到底是何方神圣
And then I'll figure out what the hell
并阻止它
Monster Zero really is and try to stop it.
帝王组织会先找到我们
Before Monarch finds us?
我相信你的朋友会很高兴
I'm sure all your friends will be
与你重逢
very happy to see you again.
我们不能袖手旁观
We can't just sit here.
行吗？这不是我们想要的世界
All right? This isn't the world that we wanted.
我记得你说过这世界
I seem to remember you telling me
本就属于他们
that the world always belonged to them.
或许是时候将世界交还他们
Well, maybe it is time we gave it back.
马克
Mark
马克 等等  你在干嘛?
Mark, wait. What are you doing?
我们不能坐以待毙 我得做点什么
I can't just sit down there. I gotta do something.
比如?
Like what?
-比如去找我的女儿  -怎么找?
- Like go find my daughter. - How?
你去哪?
Where are you gonna go?
我只剩她了 山姆
She's the only thing I got left, Sam.
当初我们没在她身边
I wasn't there for her.
不能再让这种事发生
I'm not gonna let that happen again.
祝你好运
Good luck.
真美
Beautiful.
摩斯拉
Mothra.
怪物女王
Queen of the Monsters.
你在录音吗?
Are you recording this, Stanton?
全在录
I record everything now.
所有东西
Everything.
这像首歌
It's like a song.
我打赌只有某个怪兽
I bet there's only one thing
能听懂这首歌
that can understand this.
哥斯拉
Godzilla.
收到了
Yeah, I got it.
接收到回应 载入中
Picking up a reply. Bringing it up.
他还活着
He's still alive.
所以她和哥斯拉 他们是
So, her and Godzilla, they're like...
是在谈恋爱吗?
They got a thing going on?
这有点乱 对吗?
That's kind of messed up, right?
两种不同物种间的共生关系
Symbiotic relationships between two different species
也不是啥奇闻
aren't all that uncommon.
你能追踪他吗?
Can you track him?
不行 信号太弱
No. Signal's too weak.
但也许她可以
But maybe she can.
你们有多少核弹头?
How many nukes do you have?
干嘛?
Why?
我们可以帮助他
We could help him.
华府上方的六级飓风
This category six hurricane over D.C.
就是王者基多拉的巢穴
is where King Ghidorah is nesting.
这会是项结合
Working with all four branches of the military,
四大军种的联合行动
this will be a joint operation
将其诱离本土
to lure it away from the mainland,
让我们有足够时间疏散群众
so that we can continue evacuations long enough
并让潜艇小组完成任务
for our submersible team to complete its mission.
所以这就是死马当活马医的任务 对吗？
So this plan is what you would call a "long shot," right?
这群书呆子带核弹
What do those nerds think they're gonna do
去海底干嘛？
down there with a bunch of nukes?
你没听说吗 格里芬?
You ain't hear 'em, Griffin?
他们想把哥斯拉起死回生
They wanna bring Godzilla back from the dead.
我们在海底时我们将转战别区
We'll be out of range while you're down there,
但会有中队
but a squadron will stay behind
守护你们
to keep an eye out for you.
感激不尽
Appreciate it.
好了 鲍曼 下潜吧
All righty, Bowman,
开始下潜
let's take her down.
下潜 设定深度150米
Dive the ship. Make depth 150.
祝你们好运
Good luck.
谢谢 山姆
Thanks, Sam.
我们需要好运
We'll need it.
现在是什么时候？
What time is it?
该换新表的时间
Time to get a new watch.
这是安德鲁最喜欢的笑话
Andrew's favorite joke.
只要有人拿出表
You never took that watch out of your pocket
他就会这么问
without him asking that question.
若你在五年前告诉我
You told me five years ago,
我会试图拯救杀儿凶手
I'd be trying to save the thing that took my son,
因为只有靠他
that would be the only way
去拯救我的家人
to save the family I have left...
有时
Sometimes,
治愈伤口的唯一方法
the only way to heal our wounds is to make peace
就是与创造他们的恶魔谈和
with the demons who created them.
你真的相信吗?
You really believe that?
你不是吗?
Don't you?
这就是你在这的原因吗?
Isn't that why you are here?
马克 有些事超出了我们的理解
There are some things beyond our understanding, Mark.
我们必须接受他们并向他们学习
We must accept them and learn from them,
因为这些危机时刻
because these moments of crisis
也是信仰的潜在时刻
are also potential moments of faith.
在那一刻
A time
我们走到一起共度难关或是分崩离析
when we either come together or fall apart.
大自然总有一种平衡自己的方式
Nature always has a way of balancing itself.
唯一的问题是
The only question is,
我们将扮演什么角色?
what part will we play?
你是即兴扯淡扯出来的?
Did you just make that up?
不是
No.
我之前在幸运饼干上读到的
I read it in a fortune cookie once.
很长的饼干
A really long fortune cookie.
船况如何?
Status of the ship?
遭遇某种漩涡 船长
Some sort of vortex, Captain.
在拉我们下潜 1600英尺后撞击
It's dragging us. 1600 feet till impact.
800英尺
800 feet.
200英尺后撞击
Emergency blow  200 feet
一百
One hundred
二十五
Twenty-five
准备迎接撞击
Brace for impact
亚果 这是布罗迪号
Argo, this is U.S.S. Brody
在前往疏散途中
en route to evacuation perimeter.
装备武器 随时准备与巨兽交战
Weapons hot. Ready to engage Titans on your command.
老天
Jesus.
好像整个天空都是活的
It's like the whole sky's alive.
因为的确如此
That's because it is.
开始吧
Here we go.
报告状况
Status report.
无法确认位置 定位系统失效
Can't fix our position. GPS is down.
但惯性系统指出
But inertial says we're...
启航后前进了966公里
600 miles from departure.
不可能
That can't be.
我就知道
I knew it, man
这漩涡是通往地心空洞的隧道
The vortex was a tunnel into the Hollow Earth.
那些地底通道系统
It's a subterranean tunnel system
贯穿整个地球
that connects the entire planet.
没关系 我就知道我是对的
It doesn't matter. I knew I was right.
-我告诉过你了 小陈  -闭嘴 瑞克
- I told you, Chen  - Shut up, Rick.
一秒后紧急上浮向前进
One second emergency blow forward.
博士?
Doctor?
发射探测器
Launch probes.
范围 1 000 米
Range 1,000 meters.
相机没问题
Camera good.
控制住范围
Holding range.
继续
Steady.
天哪
Jesus.
向右平移
Pan right.
看起来像埃及
Looks Egyptian.
或是罗马的文物
Or Roman.
不 这些不同
No, this is something different.
这些 这些更古老
This is... This is way older.
不是吧
Oh, my.
所有的传说
All of the legends,
和那些故事
the stories,
都是真的
they are true.
他们真的是第一批神祗
They really were the first gods.
如果土地和石头会说话
If only the earth and stones could speak,
会诉说多么精彩的故事啊
the stories they could tell us.
斯坦顿博士
Doctor Stanton,
有哥斯拉的踪迹吗
any sign of Gojira?
有 探测器检测到微量的辐射
Yeah, the probe is picking up a radioactive blob,
在山脊另一边
just past that ridge.
设定航向
Set a course.
请注意
Attention, please.
总统下令
Martial law has now been instated
全面戒严
by order of the President.
波士顿地区
The greater Boston area
现归军方管辖
is now under control of the U.S. Military.
市民请前往邻近疏散中心报道
All citizens to report to the nearest evacuation center
立即疏散
for immediate transport.
重复 所有市民
I repeat, all citizens
请前往疏散中心报到
are to report to the nearest evacuation...
泰坦巨兽引起的
Massive storms and other disasters
大型风暴和灾难
triggered by the Titans
迫使数百万人逃离主要城市
have forced millions to flee major cities.
由于华府收到六级飓风重创
And with D.C. hit hard by a category six hurricane
让首都完全泡在水中
that has left the capital completely flooded,
这是人类史上最大的灾难
this is the single greatest disaster in human history.
救援搜救行动持续进行
The grim search continues, as people around the world
全国民众仍努力在残骸中寻找
sift through the debris of leveled homes
希望找到失踪的亲人
in the hope of finding missing loved ones.
这景象虽让人心碎
And though this sight is heartbreaking,
但并非个例
it is unfortunately nothing unique.
全球各大城市都遭遇了
Cities around the globe have fallen
众人口中的
under the wake of what many are calling
泰坦崛起
"The Rise of the Titans."
我觉得我们应该停下
I think we should stop.
为什么？
Why?
因为我还想繁衍后代
'Cause I still wanna have kids one day.
不希望胜生出带鳍的孩子
Preferably without flippers.
全面暂停 原地待命
All stop. Hover the ship.
哇噢
Whoa.
侦测到氧气 二氧化碳及甲烷
We got O2, CO2, and methane.
里面似乎有某种气体
It looks like there's some sort of air pocket in there.
天啊
My God.
那是哥斯拉
Zilla.
再见 探测器  返回最后一个画面
- And goodnight, Gracie. - Pull up the last frame.
-对  -那里
- Yup. - There.
辐射的源头
The source of the radiation.
所以他才回到这里
That's why he returned here.
他在进食
He's feeding,
再生
regenerating.
这是他家
This is his home.
他就是靠这个才活了这么久
This is how he's survived for so long.
始终在调整 进化
Always adapting, evolving.
太惊人了
It's incredible.
所以 它自己能搞定
So, dude's got this covered.
是吗? 它只需要睡一小会
Right? He just needs a little nap.
不是
No.
这个过程可能需要数年时间
This process could take years.
我们得按计划进行
We have to proceed as planned.
等等
Hang on.
我们要发射核弹
We're gonna launch a nuclear torpedo
给大怪兽做心肺复苏
in order to revive a giant monster.
好吧 这 这不像
Okay, this is... This is not like
发动抛锚汽车那么简单
we're just jump-starting a car.
我们还有另一个难题
We have another complication.
武器系统在坠落中损毁
Our weapons systems were damaged during the crash.
我们没法发射
We can't launch.
没办法修复吗？
Can it be repaired?
我想恐怕是的
I'm afraid not.
如果进去里面设计时器
Okay. What if we go inside, set a timer,
手动引爆呢？
and blow up the warhead manually?
不可能的 就算没被高温烤死 辐射也会致命
No way. If the heat doesn't fry you, the radiation will.
我去吧
I'll go.
你在讲什么鬼话
What the hell does that mean?
肯定有别的办法
There must be another way.
没时间争论了
There's no time for debate.
我去吧
I'll go.
亚果 我们弹药不足
Argo, we are red on ammo
快坚持不住了
and low on fuel. We can't take much more of this
收到 收到 尽量牵制他们一会
Copy, copy. Just hold them off as long as you can.
上校 你看
Colonel, take a look at this.
所有巨兽都停下了
All the Titans have stopped.
他们现在又着了什么魔?
What the hell has gotten into them now?
目前所有攻击
It does appear as if the attacks
似乎都暂停了
have ceased for the time being,
全部巨兽在几分钟内
with the creatures going from destructive to docile
从大肆破坏转为温顺
within minutes.
没人知道为何或其中缘由
Now, no one is sure how or why,
但这似乎在全球同步发生
but this seems to be happening simultaneously around the world.
怎么了?
What's going on?
奥卡
The ORCA.
什么?
What?
真不知谁有如此能耐
I wonder who could have done this.
麦蒂?
Maddie?
麦蒂
Maddie.
第一次接触 你会开始
First contact, you're gonna start
失去这种视力
losing your long-range vision.
进入氧气室后
When you surface,
你的运动技能会开始消退
your motor skills are gonna start to fade,
但我放了一个氦氧混合物在水箱里
but I put a helioxed mixture in the tank,
这应该能帮你保持稳定一点
which should help you stay stable a little longer.
这是项荣耀
It was an honor, man.
谢谢
Thank you.
我的笔记本
My notes.
你确定吗?
Are you sure?
他为我们战 为我们死
He fought for us, died for us.
他不但是我们可能和平共存的实证
He's not only proof that coexistence is possible,
更是其中的关键
he is the key to it.
照顾好他们 马克
Take care of them, Mark.
鲍曼 全速返航
Bowman, take us out, fast.
好的 船长
Aye, Captain.
他已脱离母船
He's clear.
再见了…
…老朋友
你还好吗?
You all right?
鲍曼 发个求救型号给亚果
Bowman, send a distress message to the Argo.
好的 船长
Aye, Captain.
有看到什么吗?
See anything?
大家别动
Nobody move
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
我知道怎么找到他们
I know how to find 'em.
I know how to find 'em
让他以我们为傲 千万别搞砸
Let's make him proud and not screw this up.
他是怎么 呃
How did he, uh...
为救我们而牺牲
By saving us.
山姆 现在情况怎么样？
Sam, what've we got going on?
我们认为艾玛在激活奥卡
We think Emma activated the ORCA
在波士顿附近
somewhere near Boston.
所以基多拉和哥斯拉
That's why Ghidorah and Godzilla
才会同时朝那去里
are both headed that way now.
但我们仍不能确定确切地点
But we haven't been able to pinpoint the exact location
因为少了特定的奥卡讯号对比
without the missing piece of the ORCA signal.
我有缺失的讯号
I've got the missing piece.
这是哥斯拉 对吧?
It's Godzilla, right?
-我们已经试过了  -这不是哥斯拉
- I know we already tried. - It's not Godzilla.
这是我们
It's us.
你说的我们是什么意思?
What do you mean "us"?
艾玛吧哥斯拉和人类的生物声学混合到一起
Emma combined the bioacoustics of Godzilla with a human.
这就是她如何制作的奥卡
That's how she made the signal for the ORCA.
其他生物认为这是另一个顶级捕食者
The creatures just think it's another apex predator.
嗯 这就说的通了
Well, that makes sense.
我们的确是一群好色又残暴的肉食者
I mean, we are a bunch of horny murderous carnivores.
好有哲理 现在怎么办？
Yeah, that's real poetic. Now what?
我们追踪它 锁定它 然后把我女儿抢回来
We track it, we find it, and we get my daughter back.
这些马路三宝怎么办？
What about Moe, Larry, and Curly over here?
哥斯拉会重建平衡
Godzilla will bring balance.
我懂了 用芹泽让他们自己开打那招
Oh, I get it. A little Serizawa let-'em-fight action.
我以前超爱听他那么说
I used to love it when he said that.
不 这次我们要加入战斗
No. This time, we join the fight.
你知道你在干嘛吗
What do you think you're doing?
我没时间和你吵 乔纳
I don't have time to argue about this, Jonah.
我要把我的麦蒂找回来
I'm getting Maddie back.
我的人不能带走
Not with my men, you're not.
艾玛 你说这是为了世界大局
Emma, you said this was about the greater good.
地球应该被清理一次
That the planet deserved a clean slate.
但你现在却准备
But now you're prepared
把大家置于险境
to put all our lives in danger
就因为你的小女儿不见了？
because your little girl is missing.
奥卡正
The ORCA is with...
奥卡已经不重要了
The ORCA no longer matters.
人类无法控制自然法则
Man does not control the laws of nature.
你也不能
And neither do you.
我已经失去了一个孩子 不能再失去另一个
I already lost one child. I'm not losing another.
我必须救他
I have to fix this.
让她走
Let her go.
我们要的都得到了
We have everything we need.
哦 完了
Oh, shit
好了 锁定奥卡讯号最后一个音
Okay, we've zeroed in on the last ping from the ORCA.
芬威公园 正前方
Fenway Park, dead ahead.
我们会用火力分散基多拉的注意力
We'll lay cover fire to keep Ghidorah distracted.
收到
Copy that.
上校 所有中队锁定目标
Colonel, all squadrons are locked on target.
为芹泽复仇
For Serizawa.
是我眼花还是它体格升级了？
Is it just me or has he been working out?
帮帮忙 别逗我了
Are you kidding me?
芹泽给它吃了大力丸
Serizawa's got that lizard juiced
太他妈厉害了
Damn right.
小伙子们 哥斯拉的辐射
Oh, boy. Godzilla's radiation levels
要爆表了
are going through the roof.
在他产生热核反应前我们有12分钟
We got about 12 minutes before he goes thermonuclear.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
意思是12分钟后
I'm saying in about 12 minutes,
红袜主场要被夷平了
it's gonna be a bad day to be a Red Sox fan.
伙计们 快找回奥卡
Okay, guys, you need to find the ORCA,
救回麦蒂 然后闪人
get Madison, and get the hell out of there.
芹泽对哥斯做了什么
Whatever Serizawa did to Godzilla
有点过了
worked a little too well.
他会像原子弹一样爆炸
'Cause he's about to explode like an atom bomb.
收到
Roger that.
准备着陆
Prepare for landing.
上上上
Go, go, go
-分散前进  -在我左翼插进
- Spread out  - Flank left
跟着我
On me
麦蒂森
Madison
我这有发现 这边
I got something  Over here.
过来看看
Come check this out
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
我找到奥卡了 看起来损毁严重
I found the ORCA, sir, it looks pretty banged up
没看到你女儿
No sign of your daughter.
她不在这
She's not here
我们得离开这了
We gotta get out of here
走走
Let's go
上车
Get in
来啦
Incoming
上车
Get in
格里芬 你还好吗?
Griffin, you all right?
马丁内兹 帮我把她抬上去
Martinez, let's get her up.
麦蒂森在哪?
Where's Madison?
我不知道  我觉得她在这
I don't know. I thought she was there
哦？她不在这
Well, she's not there
放松
Take it easy
按住那边  好的 好的
- Get that side. - Okay, okay.
小心
Look out
我希望你找人的本事
I hope you're as good
和你把人弄丢的本事一样好
at finding her as you are losing her.
我没弄丢她 她自己跑走了
I didn't lose her, she ran away.
哦？我真不知道为什么
Well, gee, I wonder why
不怪那孩子
I can't blame that kid.
如果我有你们俩这样的父母
If I had these two for parents,
我也会离家出走
I'd have run away from home, too.
你刚说啥?
What did you just say?
如果我有你们俩这样的父母
If I had the two of you for parents,
我也会离家出走
I'd run away from home, too.
老家
Home.
哥斯拉的辐射值已到达临界点
Godzilla's radiation's reaching critical mass.
6分钟后他就要炸了
Six minutes until he blows.
命令剩余中队撤退
Order all remaining craft to retreat
麦蒂
Maddie
麦蒂森
Madison
麦蒂
Maddie
麦蒂森
Madison
艾玛
Emma
麦蒂
Maddie
马丁内兹
Martinez
找到了 数到三
We got it. On three.
一 二 三
One, two, three...
用力抬
Lift together.
哦 我的宝贝
Oh, my baby.
她还有呼吸吗?
Is she breathing?
马克 她还有呼吸吗?
Mark, is she breathing?
麦蒂
Maddie.
妈妈
Mom.
-爸爸 -嘘
- Dad. - Shh.
-妈妈 妈妈  -我们在这
- Mom. Mom. - We're here.
收到
Roger that.
鱼鹰直升机两分钟后抵达
Osprey's coming in two minutes.
我们得动作快点了
We gotta work fast.
要干嘛？
To do what?
你确定要这么做？
You sure about this?
只有这方法能救他
It's the only way to save him.
我们修好机器 坐上直升机
We fix it, get on the osprey
吸引那怪兽远离哥斯拉
and draw that thing away from Godzilla.
让他有时间恢复
Buy him time to get back on his feet.
马克 你知道那怪兽的能耐
Mark, you've seen what that thing can do.
我知道很危险 但必须冒这个险
I know. It'll be tight, but we have to take that chance.
准备好了吗
Are you good to go?
是的
Yes.
好了 一 二
All right. One, two,
三
three.
成功了
That's it.
That's it
格里夫 找到你了
Come on, Griff. We got you.
来 艾玛 我们走
Come on, Emma. Let's go.
好 你带她先走
Okay. Take her. Take her
我得激活机器
I still have to activate it.
什么？
What?
我随后就来 去吧
I'm right behind you. Go
我们走 我们走
Let's go, let's go
妈妈
Mom
走 麦蒂
Come on, Maddie
走 走 走
Go, go, go
除了腿还有哪疼吗
You got any pain anywhere besides your leg?
我们得立即起飞
We gotta lift off, now
等等
Wait
艾玛 走了 快  快
Emma, let's go  Come on
妈妈
Mom
Mom.
我爱你
I love you.
不
No.
-不  -艾玛
- No  - Emma
妈妈
Mom
不
No.
妈妈
Mom
王者万岁
Long live the king.
天哪
Jesus.
还好他是我们这边的
Good thing he's on our side.
目前是如此
For now.
你们看
Look.
哥斯拉
怪兽之王
马拉岛
这是一个崭新的世界 朋友
It's a brave new world, my friend.
像这种东西
Such things as this
自从怪兽称王后就更值钱了
become much more valuable since the rise of the king.
乡亲们要的并不多
My men, they don't ask for much.
无法在这捕鱼
Can't fish here anymore.
海洋生物全死了
Everything's dead.
我们买了
We'll take it.